I appreciate there
are a lot of bellends online all talking
about making money.
I just want to make one thing clear.
I'm making these videos not so you can get
rich.
This is about providing for your families,
escaping financial stress, and
just having more confidence within
whatever it is you want to do without
burning
out. There's a famous saying
that says you should choose a lazy person
to do a hard
job because they will find an easy way of
doing it.
I'm not sure I agree with
that because I've hired some lazy people
before, and I
sacked the fuckers.
And counterintuitively, in this video,
I'm going to teach you
how to make less content,
rely on email marketing less, so you
don't have to worry about interesting
things to email people about,
how to do less
or no sales calls,
and how to avoid repeating yourself.
I think the dog wants to come in to say
hello.
Declan, you best get him in the edit,
mate.
It's going to warm the hearts of people
around the world.
Now you behave yourself, all right?
And I will say this from the off.
I am a very lazy marketer,
and I like to play
business in easy mode.
This lazy business mode has generated
me over $3 million US since, let's say,
December 2023. So that's $5,402
a day. Now,
I still have to work every single day for
that money to come in, and
I'll explain that process a little bit
later in the video.
If you ground me, we're working.
Working equals walking.
You pipe down. However,
I just did the biggest dickhead
thing that anyone in this space can do.
I just showed you my business-to-business
revenue.
And the majority of you
are not in the realm of business to
business, you're in the
realm of business to consumer.
And the reason that you shouldn't take
Stripe
screenshots on face value
when they're put in front of you by
dickheads on YouTube,
including myself, is this.
Ad spend isn't accounted into that.
For all you know,
I could have spent $2 million in all
that period of time
in paid ads to make $3 million in revenue,
of which $1 million was profit or
less. And all I'm showing you
is the big number.
You don't get to see profit and revenue.
You don't get to see take-home.
You don't know about business partners
and other things.
Ad spend in the B2B world has a much
larger ROAS, and ROAS means
return on ad spend.
The likeliness of you being able to spend
$100 acquiring someone
and getting $5 to $1,000 out of it, that
happens in the B2B world.
It doesn't happen so much in the B2C
world, and I'll
explain in a second. And the reason
that B2B sales are of a much bigger amount
of cash, people are like,
"How the hell are you spending thousands
of dollars on a
course?" It's because of the factor of
something called return on investment.
If I PT you, your return on investment
is money gone, look better naked
back. If you buy Nutonic,
your return on investment is money gone,
maybe more productive back. But
if you work as an employee, unless you
have a bonus structure
or commission structure,
that productivity may not yield a
financial return. And the way
that this business works
is whatever information I
give you, you can very simply
and actionably make money from it.
For instance,
there'll be a link in the description to a
$99 content creation
course. Teaches you how to film content,
what to say and what order, how to chop it
up and edit it. It's $99 US.
For most people, if they were to buy that
course and make better content,
how many clients do they need to take on
board to
make their money back? One.
There's also actually another one in there
that teaches
people how to use email marketing.
Again, all they need is one good email,
and they make the money back.
So because in the B2B world,
I can promise you
that whatever money you give me,
you're going to see back in revenue for
your own business, it's a lot easier to
make sales.
So it's only a little bit charlatanistic,
is that a word?
To show you my rev
and then for you to go away and think,
"Oh, maybe I could
make..." You can't. B2B
is completely different.
And one of the reasons you're probably
like, "Why does James always plug his $99
courses?" I'll tell you why.
Because we have about a 90%,
10% upsell on that.
The amount of people
that do those courses make their $99 back
really fast.
Then they're like,
"What's the most next expensive thing I
can buy?" One in
ten.
So don't believe me on my revenue
that I showed you before.
Instead,
let's look at my fitness business,
which is B2C.
Here we have $15 million. And this
is just through Stripe.
We also have in-app payments, PayPal.
There's a huge chunk of revenue
that we take in that's not through Stripe,
but for
the sake of argument here. Now,
I'll be honest as well.
That started in August 2017. Now,
this works out to
$3,534 US per day since launch. And
this is using the exact same lazy
marketing formula.
So I've shown you
that I can make revenue as B2B,
but I've also shown you I could
do it as B2C.
The majority of gurus out there can't do
that. They don't do that.
They sit there going, "Guys,
my e-com drop shipping business." My
missus has been wearing these, right?
Because the lenses on them are disgusting,
abhorrent.
There's a few things
that I will not accept,
as young Declan knows.
If you plant one fingerprint on the screen
of my laptop, you
might as well just leave work
and never come back.
And the second that someone has the
audacity to put their dirty, grubby
fingerprints on my sunglasses.
I quite like wearing these. These
are quite cool.
Now, one of the reasons
that I'll be completely honest with you,
right?
And this is going to sound like I'm a
terrible business person, but I'm going to
say it anyway.
With Affordable Online Coaching,
previously James' Academy, with my
online coaching business,
we spend more a year in Stripe fees,
yes, Stripe fees,
than we do in advertising.
The reason being is
that our margins aren't big enough for us
to have a
leeway of capital to use to acquire new
customers.
Because the business
is of a low margin nature
and keeping things
affordable,
we don't have money to play with.
And when we decided to scale the fitness
business, that's just the way it is.
So every single dollar
that you saw there of the $3,500 a day for
eight years
has all been made through not only organic
content, but the very lazy marketing
formula we're about to get into. Now,
I don't primarily just work with personal
trainers,
but if you're a personal trainer,
there's another link in the
description, and that is a course for PTs.
Teach you how to run your in-person
business and what content to create to
stand
out. And again, $99.
All of these things in the description are
business expenses. So whether you're a PT,
an estate agent, whatever it is, if
you buy something from me,
you just download the invoice,
put it in your Dropbox
with your accountants.
At the end of the year,
they reduce it off your
profitability. So the original promise
was less content, not relying heavily on
coming up with email marketing campaigns,
not to do sales calls or do a lot less of
them, and to not repeat yourself.
Let's get into this on a granular level.
The current ways to make money online,
there are three real ways that people
online are promoting.
You probably got your drop shipping bros,
unpredictable, high
risk,
and just probably increasingly difficult
with the current landscape of people
doing it.
Then some people out there try
and sell software, but it can be
expensive.
You need a lot of capital to begin with.
You probably need some investors Again,
unless you've got a team of developers to
produce that software,
you would want to start in a position of
having loads of
money. Again, Ed Lawrence,
when he built RevTrack, which
is the software you can
use to see where money's coming in through
your YouTube leads.
That's probably something you want a
little bit further down the line
when you've
got some businesses that
are doing really well.
Then another one would probably be
affiliate marketing,
which a lot of people can
get suckered into. They go,
"I'm going to create a big social media
channel so that
I can promote other people's products
and get a kickback." Okay.
But remember, every product
that we sell has a profit margin.
You're only getting a small amount of
that margin. So a profit share, all right.
And I suppose AdSense
and getting paid from YouTube in ad
revenue is the
same thing. YouTube's like, "Right,
we're making this much money.
You can have a little bit of it." Same way
that you do affiliate marketing.
You might promote AG1.
They're just giving you a little bit of
the money.
And my best advice to any of you thinking
of going down that route is don't.
Sell something of your own.
Sell your own product because then you can
make all of
the money from that sale,
and you don't have to rely on big views.
This channel, in particular,
doesn't have to rely on big views.
Because rather than Google paying me in an
AdSense, I haven't even got monetization
turned on on this channel. I pay myself.
So the four stages of lazy marketing
that you need to implement into your
business
go like this. You can make less content
if your content performs
better. I'll repeat that.
If your content isn't performing,
you can end up doing
one, two, three reels a day.
If you're doing any more than one video a
day, your
content isn't performing,
and instead of making more content,
you need to make that
content better.
The first thing you need to do
is to think out your hook.
What is the first thing you're saying in
content?
If you say things like,
"You need to..." "With my clients,
one thing I
find..." "What's worked for me is..."
Rubbish.
You've got to imagine the majority of the
internet, if someone doesn't know you,
they don't like you. As a default setting,
they do not like you.
You're an unfamiliar face on their screen.
Whole world doesn't like you.
Just think of it that way. So
when you come onto camera and your hook
is about you,
they don't care. They don't care, and
if the majority of the flipping world
don't
know who you are,
the majority of the world don't care.
So instead, you need to open
and start content with the person
in mind whose problems you're solving.
Give me
just a random topic. Anything.
And then I'm going to try
and find a way to make
this bottle an analogy. All right. Okay.
How about this? Say you're an accountant.
You would write on the side of this bottle
the tax thresholds.
We've got 20%, 30%, 40%, 45%.
You could then use the visual hook of
saying, "These are the tax
brackets that your income fits into at the
end of the financial year.
And if you wanted to pay less tax,
I want you to think about this." So
straight
away, someone who's tax-conscious,
tax-savvy, is seeing that
visualization in front of them,
and they're going, "Oh." Then you're like,
"If you
listen to this,
I'm going to tell you how to save more
tax." Any person that wants
to save tax is going to listen.
Then what you do is you fill up
that bottle with,
let's say, $100,000 worth of liquid.
You then bring a copycat bottle into shot,
and you go, "If you had a
family trust with your partner as a
beneficiary,
you could take the same amount of
income," then you pour it into the second
bottle, "and you could split it through
two people's tax returns."
And then you could do the maths of the
saving, and
someone could have gone,
"Do you know what?
I've heard about having a family trust.
I've heard of beneficiaries,
but I've never really understood what it
meant.
Your visual with the two bottles helped me
understand it forever." But if you start
a video going, "Basically, when I
was learning about accountings back in the
day,
one thing that really helped me
was imagining there was a bottle,"
you're like, "Mate." First of all,
you're talking about yourself.
Second of all, talk about them.
In fitness, you don't go,
"I've been eating this
breakfast for three years now,
and it's really helped me lose weight."
You say, "If
you're someone that's looking to lose
weight, there's a breakfast out there that
could help you lose weight
that you wouldn't get bored of,
and it would help you
get the results you want.
So for any of you out there
that don't like the idea of
having to fast until 1:00 PM,
let me share with you
that recipe." Because the
story's still the same.
You can always get to the end of
that video and say, "And
the best thing is,
I ate this for three years
and I never got bored, so you won't
either." When it comes to high-performing
content, the better your content
performs, the less of it you have to make.
The better you get at creating content
and course correcting over time, you could
get to a position where you're putting out
one, two, three pieces of content a
week, and it's enough. Again,
content course, link in description.
When you want to come to do less email
marketing,
one of the best things you can do
is create an autoresponder.
So for instance,
rather than me having to email people
every day, which I did for years
and kind of burnt out,
I've created multiple
different squeeze pages around the
internet where, for instance, this one,
30 days
to improve your business in 30 days.
You put your email in there.
Over the next 30 days,
I come in with just a really good bit of
advice you can
implement your business.
If you want to copy that or see how
that works, I'll put
the link to that in the description as
well.
And the average person buys on
that between days 19 and 21.
Now, the beautiful thing about this
is once you've written this sequence,
you don't
have to do it again.
So you want to pre-write all of your email
automations so that
when someone gets to a certain point in
your sales process, even watching this
video, when they subscribe,
the email's already pre-written in a
sequence ready to
go.
If you set up those automations over the
next three, six, nine months, you now
write less emails and still have an equal,
if not much better
impact on those person nurturing
sequences.
Then you can be quite clever as well.
Not everyone wants email marketing.
So again, there's this lead magnet
that I'm using at the moment where I'm
promoting
how to structure a sales page to be the
most efficient.
Again, people not only get the asset,
they get put into an email automation.
My lazy marketing, first of all,
if I can make content
and package it well enough,
I can make less content. Second of all,
every single sales email is pre-written,
so when I put you into a nurturing
sequence, everything's automated.
And all of that throughout the days
is going to push people into different
places
and go to ultimately the very next thing
we're going to talk about now.
When it comes to doing less
or no sales calls altogether,
rather than sitting
on a call and chatting to someone
and nurturing them for half an hour,
my email
automations do that. So that
when you get to my website, you're already
semi-nurtured to the point
that you just need to decide whether
or not you want to
buy or not. So again,
I'll put a link to this page so you can
have a look in the
description.
There's going to be a lot of links in the
What are you going to do? Call the cops?
Everything you need to know about the
course is here.
Absolutely everything, from testimonials,
facts about it.
The whole idea is
that by putting every single bit of
information on this page, you
don't need to jump on a call.
You don't need to talk to anyone.
And this again stems through laziness.
I have never and will never jump on a
sales call for any product or anything I'm
selling. Because if you say, "James,
I need to talk to someone to buy a can of
No
Tonic," or,
"I need to talk to someone to join your
course," or, "I need to talk to
someone to join your training app,"
fundamentally, there's a crack
and a weakness
in my sales process thus far. And there
is a life for everyone where they can
step back and do less
and create automations so
that on a daily basis, all you need
to do is create videos. Think about this,
for instance.
This very video is me doing exactly what
I- I'm saying.
All I've got to do is sit here
and talk for what? 12, 13 minutes.
There's now going to be thousands of
people going to different links, different
automations,
and different landing pages to then
qualify themselves to becoming
clients.
These rev track data set points here
are only about a week old, but as you
can see,
there are thousands of dollars of
attribution of revenue coming in through
every single YouTube video.
These sales are coming from the exact lazy
system that
I'm talking about.
So we spoke about drop shipping not being
great.
We spoke about the world of software
and affiliate marketing not being the best
way to generate revenue. So what
is the best way to generate revenue?
There's a pretty bad reputation at the
moment online for course bros or people
selling digital courses,
and I suppose I am one of them.
But the $99 courses to me aren't just
standalone courses, they're actually lead
magnets.
And they're lead magnets where I'm giving
quite a lot of value and I'm
actually getting people to buy into a
certain amount because I want them to
experience what it's like to give me money
and get a result.
But then my mentorship,
although technically is a course, it's
actually a service and a product combined,
and that's where I see the future.
So even if you're a personal trainer,
you don't sell a course,
you sell a product
and a service combined. The product
is the system in which you implement with
clients. It might be a training regime,
it might be the way you approach calorie
deficit,
it might be the way you approach muscle
growth.
But the service is the interaction you
have with the client every day.
So for instance,
just having a look in our Discord here.
People aren't just paying me for a course,
they're paying me for the service,
giving people feedback, talking to them.
If we look at people with their wins
and the things that they're getting
through at
the moment and the different lessons
and questions they want to ask.
And this is the best way
that I could say it to anyone out there.
If you want to do this product
and service thing, the laziest
and best and most
efficient way is this.
Work with people in a realm
that they communicate with you,
ask you questions, do whatever.
And whenever you see common themes,
build it out
into a small educational course.
So for instance, within this course, when
we launched it, we realized
that there were some people
that really wanted to ask a
lot about content. So I went away
and I created a short form content course.
I gave it to everyone that's paying me,
but then I created it as a lead magnet.
Then I was spotting there
were a lot of questions about email
marketing, so I
created an email marketing course,
gave it to everyone inside the mentorship,
made
it as a lead magnet. The same with
that landing page lead magnet.
Whatever I'm seeing people struggle with
inside, I'm creating a video resource so I
don't have to repeat myself so much.
But at the same time,
I'm then making a version of it
that I can use as a lead
magnet. So if you're, again,
I'll use it as an example,
personal trainer.
You work with people one-to-one, and
if they keep having recurring themes, like
they don't know what to cook.
You go away and you create some easy
recipes for
your clients to have a certain amount of
protein and whatever.
You then give those resources to your
clients for free,
then you give some away as
a lead magnet.
Then some of your clients say, "Hey,
I'm really struggling to feel
comfortable with the squat rack." You go,
"Cool." You create a resource so that
people feel comfortable using their techno
gym squat rack, fucking whatever squat
rack it is.
You give it to your clients for free.
You take it, a version of it,
you create it as a lead magnet.
Your clients then say to you,
"Ah." What's the issue one of your clients
are
having, PTing? Can't squat deep enough.
You get a squat mobility program that's in
big depth.
You give it to your clients for free.
You create a resource that's a little bit
shorter. Use it as a lead magnet.
That is where the future is going.
Whether you're a physio,
whether you're a PT,
whether you're an accountant,
whether you're in real estate,
whatever it is, there
is a perfect combination of product
and service that gives people the exact
thing
that they want. And the best part is,
once you've created these systems, which I
teach people how to do,
all you need to do is turn up,
make content, honing in
on a problem,
and people will trickle themselves down,
and they will end up in your
welcome thread saying hello.
This little green icon here that
signifies people are new.
I don't talk to someone at all until
they've paid me.
And any business,
any person can have this too.
Better yet, if you're someone who's lazy,
it doesn't actually have to be a
weakness.
You can turn it into a massive strength.
Hope you enjoyed this video, and
if you got a lot of information from this,
check
out the links in the description.
If you're not quite ready to buy any of my
stuff,
check out this video here because the
boffins at YouTube reckon this
is one you'll
really enjoy. Go!